clearbooks.co.uk 2012-12-21

# Privacy « Small Business Cloud Software – Online Accounting, Payroll

**At Clear Books we recognise the importance of your privacy. This policy outlines the information we collect, how we use it and how we safeguard your information.**

Clear Books may be required to revise this Privacy Policy in the future to comply with any applicable European regulations, in order to utilise new technologies or to improve your Clear Books experience, so please check back periodically.

This Privacy Policy forms part of, and should be read in conjuction with, our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.clearbooksltd.com/terms/).

### When you access Clear Books

Clear Books uses [cookies](http://www.clearbooksltd.com/cookies/) to store and collect information about your usage of the Website in order to enhance your online experience and to help us improve the quality of our services.

When you access Clear Books, your computer automatically sends us information such as the URL on our Website that you have visited, your [IP address](http://www.clearbooksltd.com/privacy/terms/), your browser type and language, and the date and time of your request.

### When you sign up to Clear Books

Clear Books collects personal information when you register on the Website. Your information will be stored confidentially by us and only used by Clear Books in order to provide you with access to our products, services and information that we believe will interest you. Your personal details will never be passed on to any other companies or third parties including affiliates and will never be added to any third party mailing lists or databases unless you opt in to do so.

Clear Books may also use information about our users in statistical aggregate form. This is non personal information and simply refers to information such as the number of registrations, traffic patterns and Website user trends.

### Opt in

If you opt in to receive free accounting advice Clear Books will share your name, organisation, location and telephone number with our approved partner accountants so that they can contact you independently. This is the only information we will share.

### When you contact us

If you contact us via email, your details and a history of the communication will be stored by us in order for us to deal with enquiries adequately and improve our customer support services.

### Your preferences and the Fubra Passport

Clear Books uses the Fubra Passport to manage the user log in process. Fubra Limited operates various other popular websites managing them via a central login system called the Fubra Passport. This system is a database of the users who can access Fubra websites and also contains a set of preferences for each subscriber.

When you sign up to a Fubra partner website, such as Clear Books, a Fubra Passport account is opened for you and you can use this to access the content on any of the Fubra websites.

As Fubra are usually providing expensive data sets to consumers free of charge, its aim has been to establish a database of subscribers who Fubra can communicate with when new features are added to current websites or when a new website is launched.

The data held in the Fubra Passport system is not available for sale to any third parties and will only ever be used with your consent.

If you would prefer not to receive alerts about Clear Books then you can manage your alerts on the My Alerts page.

If you remove all your alerts then Fubra will no longer send you any automatic update emails. However you will still remain a subscriber to Fubra websites via the Fubra Passport system and will therefore still have access to Fubra websites when you choose to search for information.

As a subscriber of the Fubra Passport, Fubra will occasionally email you with news and information about the company, new website features and new websites. If you do not wish to receive any emails from Fubra, you must cancel your subscription to the Fubra Passport login system.

Please note once you have done this you will no longer be able to log in to any Fubra websites without re-subscribing.

You can use the Fubra Passport page to join or leave any of Fubra website that is currently supported by the system. By leaving just one website you will continue to receive emails about other websites if you remain a member of those.

### Links and affiliated websites

Clear Books contains hypertext links to other sites, advertisers and other third parties. By clicking on any of these links, you are leaving our Website. Clear Books has no control over the information collected by any third party after you have left the Website. Clear Books encourages you to read their privacy policies.

The data collection and usage practices of any third party linked to Clear Books are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Clear Books assumes no liability and is not responsible for any practices of such third party web sites, including their privacy practices or content.

### Protecting your information

Clear Books uses Fubra’s secure server cluster situated in a secure data centre to protect all the information you provide us with. Fubra has invested heavily in equipment and highly qualified staff to ensure all information you enter is protected from access by any third party and only necessary and restricted access is available internally. We also protect all our connections to the Internet using various security measures including firewalls and regular security audits on all our servers.

As required by law Fubra is registered on the public register of data controllers and store and process all data in accordance with all UK legislation. Fubra is registered with the following number: Z5193400

### What is Personal Information?

Personal information is information you provide to us which personally identifies you including your name, address and e-mail address.

### What is Non Personal Information?

Non personal information is collected and recorded about users when they use the Website. This information is collected into groups so that it no longer reflects or represents any individual user and is used purely for statistical purposes.

### What is an IP address?

Each Internet connection is identified by a unique address which is referred to as an IP address (Internet Protocol address).

An IP address is made up of four numbers, separated by dots, for example: 87.124.10.1. This address allows any website visitor to be identified with the co-operation of the relevant Internet Service Provider (ISP). In practice an ISP would not give out this information because they would be in breach of the Data Protection Act. You should be aware that it is technically possible to connect an IP with a user with the help of a court order and the relevant ISP.

Some ISPs publish the name of the company or individual who uses the connection which allows anyone to see who is using that IP from central registries held by R.I.P.E. and other Regional Internet Registries (RIR). You can check if your IP address is listed using the whois service provided by all RIRs.
